<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>

<preface id="preface">
  <title>Preface</title>

  <para>
  Since this project started, we never had the time to write a real documentation.
  Thanks to the Google Summer of Code 2006, we finally had the time to write a proper 
  documentation about this project. This isn't a final version yet, we are currently 
  working on it.
  </para>

  <para>
  If you are interested by editing or translating this documentation, you should
  check the <ulink url="http://code.google.com/p/phpaspect-doc">phpAspect documentation project</ulink>.
  </para>

  <section id="preface.requirements">
    <title>Requirements</title>

    <para>
      The topic of this documentation is phpAspect, an extension of the PHP programming language
      which implement Aspect-Oriented Programming.
    </para>

    <para>
      The reader should have a good understanding of object-oriented
      programming with PHP 5. php.net has a documentation about it. A good English
      book on the subject is <xref linkend="GuBaRe2005" /> by Andi Gutmans,
      Stig Bakken, and Derick Rethans.
    </para>

    <para>
        If you want to find out more about Aspect-Oriented Programming, there is two
        excellent references: <xref linkend="Ramnivas2003" /> by Ramnivas Laddad and
        <xref linkend="Lesiecki2003" /> by Nicholas Lesiecki and Joseph D Gradecki.
    </para>
  </section>

  <section id="preface.acknowledgements">
      <title>Acknowledgements</title>

      <para>
          We would like to acknowledge Yijun Yu for his very active work on
          the Yaxx project.
      </para>
      <para>
          We would like to thank Philippe Rochat for the ideas he brought to
          this project and Fabien Nicollet who designed the phpAspect logo.
      </para>
      <para>
          We also like would to thank the PHP community for all the help they gave
          to us and Google for organizing the Google Summer of Code.
          phpAspect has been designed and developed during the Google Summer of Code 2006.
          This yearly event allows students to work on great and exciting open-source projects.
      </para>
  </section>

  <section id="preface.conventions">
    <title>Conventions Used in This Documentation</title>

    <para>
      The following is a list of typographical conventions used in this documentation:
    </para>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term><emphasis>Italic</emphasis></term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Indicates new terms, URLs, email addresses, filenames, file
            extensions, pathnames, directories, and Unix utilities.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term><literal>Constant width</literal></term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Indicates commands, options, switches, variables, functions,
            classes, namespaces, methods, modules, parameters, values,
            objects, the contents of files, or the output from commands.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term><userinput>Constant width bold</userinput></term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Shows commands or other text that should be typed literally
            by the user.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term><replaceable>Constant width italic</replaceable></term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Shows text that should be replaced with user-supplied values. 
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>

    <para>
      You should pay special attention to notes set apart from the text
      with the following styles:
    </para>

    <note>
      <para>
        This is a tip, suggestion, or general note. It contains useful
        supplementary information about the topic at hand.
      </para>
    </note>

    <warning>
      <para>
        This is a warning or note of caution.
      </para>
    </warning>
  </section>
</preface>
